<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Cosmic Leap]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Cosmic Leap</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 11:01:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 11:01:16 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Chanis]]></title><description><![CDATA[Chanis is an ancient gigastructure, the architects of which have long been lost to the unending march of time. All axes of magic converge strongly in Chanis system and seem to be harvested or focused through the stellar system turned engineered mechanism.A small red dwarf star, Lus is modulated by the orbital system that surrounds it. However, solar patterns are still somewhat unpredictable, with sunspot swarms and mild flares relatively frequent. As a result, Gris and Igris tend to have likewise somewhat unpredictable, albeit fairly mild, seasons and seasonal weather. Due to Lus’ influence, the difficulty of space navigation checks is upgraded once while made in Chanis or otherwise under the influence of Lus.Chanis is a massive artificial gigastructure orbiting a small red dwarf star colloquially known as Lus. Whatever naturally occurring planets may have once populated the Chanis system, they have long since been harvested and rendered down to provide the raw materials for the current Chanis gigastructure. Chanis comprises a number of components. Gris, a ringworld orbital ring, circumscribes Lus. A secondary and also inhabited ring, Igris, is made of enormous semi-rigidly tethered rectangular tiles and provides a diurnal cycle to Gris. Lusleen is a hollowed out moon-turned-megapolis and anchors Igris. Lusleen is the primary port of harbor and trade hub of Chanis. Finally, there is the Riverbelt, a stream of pulverized and constantly colliding spacial objects caught in the shielding mechanism that loosely wraps around all sides of Gris, provides a constantly shifting starscape to the night skies as well as a buffer against dangers such as comets and asteroids entering into Chanis and threatening Gris. The Riverbelt is also a major hazard, making it difficult to actually land ships anywhere on Gris, thus providing the ringworld and its myriad species and cultures a rather severe incidental isolation.Using the special properties of Chanis’ multiple gigantic components, magical influences are harvested and redistributed throughout the system to power, among other things, the Riverbelt, the countless slight adjustments necessary to maintain the sublimely synchronized orbits of Gris and Igris, life support systems in Igris and Lusleen, and modulations of Lus’ stellar atmosphere that would otherwise make such a (relatively speaking) tight orbit of a red dwarf star totally inhospitable to any life or even stable formulations. Moreover, the Riverbelt and the underside of Gris, which is engraved with enormous planet-sized runes, interact in such a way that the materials of the Riverbelt deposit into Gris’ underside and perpetually heal the structure and maintain the structural integrity of the ringworld.
A clue from an adventure in another system has brought the PCs to Chanis. The clue brings them first to Lusleen, where they find out that it is actually related to an isolated civilization on the surface of Gris. The civilization is hostile to outsiders and the PCs must successfully navigate the Riverbelt to reach the civilization.
Chanis is a great weapon of cosmic proportions! A villain has discovered that Chanis can be wielded in such a way that the planet-ending forces of the red dwarf, Lus, are directed through the interstitial void in between points in space to impact and obliterate planets anywhere in the galaxy. The PCs must stop the villain from gaining control of this incredible weapon--or perhaps they are the ones intent on uncovering its use and invoking its enormous power. A spacecraft has entered dangerously close to Lus’ corona and has become unresponsive. Mysterious and seemingly malicious incorporeal entities have overtaken the ship and they cannot be communicated with--they seem able to possess organics and ship systems with equal ease. The ship’s technology is fairly advanced to allow it to get so close to a star and would make valuable salvage to a group that could retrieve it.
Gris is the primary inhabited “planet” of Chanis, and all of the habitable areas exist on the inner surface of the ring (i.e., the side facing Lus and Igris). Centrifugal force provides the majority of subjective gravity on the internal side of the ring and the inside edge is approximately 0.25 AU, or 235 million kilometers, from Lus. With a circumference of approximately 1476.5M km and an 11000km width, Gris has a habitable surface area of about 1.6242034e+13 square kilometers--or a crapton of real estate as it’s known to most explorers (in comparison, Earth’s surface area is 5.101e+9 square kilometers).The diurnal period, due to the slightly slower rotational speed of Igris and its enormous rectangular shading tiles, of all inhabited regions of Gris is 26 hours split into 13 hour days and 13 hour nights. Grisians rarely track time beyond the diurnal period, as there is no significant seasonal variance. However, Gris completes a full rotation around Lus (akak., a “year”) approximately every 53.5 hours, given its tangential rotational speeds of around 1,220 km/s.Gris’ atmosphere is kept in the ring via an edgewall which extends 2000 km from the external (or “backside”) of the ring. Enormous mountains characterize the edgewall, with plentiful sheer faces and often shifting or avalanching surfaces.The internal floor of Gris extends, on average, about 400 km above the backside. As a result, there are various “underdarks” made up of subterranean systems and expanses inhabited by unique flora and fauna throughout Gris. Large, antenna-like towers that protrude from the rim of the edgewall at regular intervals are common attractions to spacefaring visitors to Chanis. These towers extend to (astronomically speaking) a fairly close range of counterpart antennae located on Lusleen. As the structures orbit within range of each other, magical energy transfers between them. This maintains a certain equilibrium within the greater structure of the entire Chanis system and is part of a cosmically sized circuit that soothes Lus (which would otherwise have wildly variable solar weather) and redirects and slows foreign objects such as meteors, comets, etc. approaching the system at dangerous vectors as a sort of shield.Gris is inhabited by myriad different species and cultures across its massive habitable surface. These species and cultures are of varying characteristics and development, but generally are not actually spacefaring. Familiarity with magic and capacity for its use also varies greatly across groups. It is not uncommon for civilizations to be totally ignorant of most others on Gris and beyond. However, travel and adventure is common across the ringworld, and though only a small handful of starfaring cultures inhabit Gris, almost all are accustomed to totally alien visitors, technologies, and magics making their way through their regions.Gris is a nexus of magical energies and all magic tends to be not only accessible but empowered and amplified while on Gris.
A crash landing due to collisions in the Riverbelt has left the PCs stranded in a technologically primitive region of Gris. The PCs will need to supplement their ship repairs with magical artifacts from the area cultures to bring the ship up to capability to make it to Lusleen.
The PCs make first contact with a Grisian culture that resides, at least partially, in one of the many underdarks of the ring. The culture has no real knowledge beyond the immediately adjacent regions, and certainly is unfamiliar with spacefaring civilizations or the technology for such.
A city on Gris is under threat from meteor rains emanating from the Riverbelt! What started as a few, if highly unusual, meteor strikes in the outlying areas has rapidly become a meteor swarm of smaller objects. It seems things will get worse--more destructive and deadlier--before they get better. Without help from the PCs, the entire city is at risk of being pulverized out of existence.
A businessman from Lusleen wants the PCs to investigate a competitor’s production facilities on Gris’ surface. For an additional fee, the businessman would like the PCs to commit some light espionage and sabotage--or some heavy sabotage involving assassination for a proportionally larger fee.
Igris is a spiraling ribbon orbiting Lus just inside the orbit of Gris. Igris comprises an 11,000 km wide ribbon with eight (8) twists and orbit at a slightly slower rate than Gris, having an orbital period of 107 hours. As a result of the slower orbital period and twists, Gris experiences a diurnal cycle. As between Gris and Igris, the ribbon completes a rotational period every 53.5 hours.Igris is home primarily to two different species that can exist in its harsh, sunwashed and airless environment: the Ethereals and the Automata. However, a number of domed cities and spaceports dot Igris’ otherwise perfectly smooth and empty surface, on both the Lus-side and the Gris-side of Igris. The domed cities house various organic and other species that cannot survive that near-vacuum of Igris’ surface.The Ethereals are made of a smokey energy that somehow maintains a generally humanoid shape. The Ethereal civilization is unfathomably ancient and thought to be as old as Chanis (or at least its current construction) itself. According to legend and rumor, the Ethereals were originally constructs of whatever forces first built Chanis, intended to maintain Gris and Igris.The Automata are not so much a species as much as a loosely related collection of sapient machine beings. The Automata are all that remains of a short-lived highly technological empire that conquered a substantial portion of Gris. Eventually the empire fell and the Automata fled to Igris where, due to the nature of their construction, they were able to flourish without worry of organic beings interfering (or enacting retribution for acts related to their imperial origin).Another remarkable feature of Igris is that it is not a “complete” ring. Igris actually extends from polar opposite sides of Lusleen, securely anchored to the labyrinthine once-moon. As Lusleen is tidally locked to Lus, it helps secure and stabilize Igris’ orbit. Igris is a realm of shadows and contrasts, and it is said that secrets hide in its every nook and cranny.
A war is brewing between the Ethereals and the Automata. The PCs have been caught up in the middle of the conflict.
A mad Automata is attempting to destroy one of the dome cities of Igris! The PCs must find a way to stop them before their plans come to fruition and countless organics die or lose their homes!
Grob Nekrteks, a technonecromancer of little renown, has converted a dome city into Grobbers--strange hiveminded hybrids blending organic tissue and Automata technology and slaved to Grob’s will. Grob and his Grobbers are expanding rapidly across Igris and rumor has it that Grob intends to sabotage Igris so that it collapses into Gris, giving the technonecromancer an endless supply of organic flesh and technological hardware to build his great technonecromantic empire!
Lusleen is, other than the red dwarf star Lus, perhaps the one remaining natural planetary structure in Chanis. Even then, however, Lus has been hollowed out over the eons to the point that the moon’s surface is little more than a regolith skin wrapping a honeycombed interior of tunnels and chambers making up Lusleen’s megalopolis. While about the size of Earth’s moon, it is in fact half the total mass as a result of the endlessly mazing tunnels, caverns, catacombs, tramways, and the like.Lusleen’s surface has no atmosphere and, outside of the various spaceports scattered across the surface that lead directly into the internal city, is entirely devoid of both organic or constructed life. Two massive structures tangentially extend 3,000 km out of each of Lusleen’s poles. These structures are used to harvest and distribute magical energies from Gris’ rotation through the systemwide circuit of Chanis.Lusleen’s interior is home to an enormous chaotic metropolis. Various governments run various districts, but the general state of Lusleen is fairly anarchic. Crime syndicates run rampant and oligarchical business consortia are the ultimate wielders of power in Lusleen. More so than anywhere else in Chanis, Lusleen principally runs on money and power--and money is necessary to buy power.It is said that if it can be bought, it can be found on Lusleen. However, the uninitiated should be wary of the price demanded, for Lusleen is a den of money-hungry vipers.
An oligarch is recruiting offworlders to gather intelligence on the competition. Whatever the PCs ultimately uncover, the oligarch will demand they follow up with a little “aggressive espionage” or will put a bounty on their heads.
Criminal syndicates are going to war and the PCs better choose a side! There will be no neutral ground in this conflict.
Deep in Lusleen there is an abandoned section of the city that is rumored to house ancient laboratories still holding untold treasures. However, just because the area is abandoned, does not mean it is uninhabited.
The Riverbelt is a vaguely defined region of pulverized materials caught in the various fields of force and influence that act as a mild sort of shield for Gris. Objects caught in the Riverbelt are pulverized to a fine dust in the Lus-facing side of the stream before being cycled to the side of the stream covering Gris’ backside. The dust on the backside is absorbed into Gris itself to repair and maintain the various structures and systems keeping the ringworld sound.The pulverizing side of the Riverbelt is a chaotic and dangerous place, where objects constantly collide and disintegrate each other into ever smaller pieces. Only the truly desperate hide in the Riverbelt and call it home--but those who are able to survive the location are generally left in isolation. Occasionally pirates and other scoundrels will try to make a living in the Riverbelt as ships necessarily have to pass through it if they wish to transit between the surface of Gris and Igris, Lusleen, or the greater cosmos beyond.An aesthetically pleasant side-effect of the Riverbelt is that it provides an artificial starry night sky to inhabitants of Gris, who would otherwise have nothing more than the pitch black of Igris above them for their night sky. Rather, the pulverizing objects reflect light back to Gris and give the Riversbelt the appearance of an ever shifting and flowing starfield.Navigating through the Riverbelt is notoriously challenging and hazards abound as variously sized particulate make meandering journeys of endless collisions. Wrecks and salvage litter the interior of the Riverbelt, both as free floating debris and as deposits upon the larger asteroids making up the dangerous flow.
Bounty hunters, Hawk and Hound, are on the prowl in the Riverbelt and are either hunting the PCs or have mistaken them for a different bounty. Hawk is an Automata able to fly independently through the void of the Riverbelt, and Hound is a sentient ship (organic, technological, or both) that primarily communicates through Hawk.
The PCs have been hired to shut down a pirate operation based out of the Riverbelt. The pirates have developed a way to protect larger asteroids from colliding with other objects in the Riverbelt and have inhabited a larger asteroid-turned fortress.
A great race through the Riverbelt is starting soon! The race is deadly and few survive to the finish line, but the rewards are great–and the destroyed ships of those who fail to finish certainly make good bonus salvage.
]]></description><link>setting/locations/chanis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Locations/Chanis.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 10:58:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Act I]]></title><description><![CDATA[
&lt;&gt;, captain of your ship, the Wandervoid, has gathered [her] most trusted crew to transport an important package to Starquarry Station Gorsk, a dwarven mining station orbiting the ringed planet Obsidish-2. The crate is large, heavy and sealed with both magic and technology proprietary to the client, the Zeltek Commission. The contract calls for delivery to Supervisor Granok personally with bioscan signature. You’ve been given a navpath and your ship has been fully refueled. Reward has been promised on delivery.
mechanical walkthrough of shipsRead the following aloud to your players:
After a lengthy journey, your ship finally emerges back into normal space in the Obsidish system just outside the extensive planetary rings of Obsidish-2. Far away but still in visual range of the Wandervoid is what is locally known as the Pommit Core, Obsidish-2's only moon and the primary source of material keeping the planet's rings thick and sprawling. The Pommit Core looks like a partially eaten apple core, the result of years of mining as well as a cataclysmic battle involving a now-slumbering god. Starquarry Station Gork is interior to Obsidish-2's rings. You begin to navigate through the rocky debris fields towards your destination.
Ask the pilot a question like:
You’ve noticed something unique about the rocky debris of the rings. What is it?
Describe the asteroids and particulates the ship passes, specifically including details from their answer. Consider emphasizing not just visual elements of the fields but also the sounds small rocks make as they bounce off hull and ship shields. This is utilizing one of the GM Principles in Daggerheart, “Ask Questions and Incorporate the Answers,” as well as a general storytelling principle of utilizing multiple sense descriptors. Then, read the following aloud:
As your ship, the Wandervoid, weaves past a large asteroid, a ping pops up on the scanners and you see another another ship floating among the stony clutter before you. It appears to be unpowered save for the apparent SOS identifying it as a Zeltek Commission ship and requesting urgent assistance. Hull metal curls at the edge of a large rend along the longitudinal axis of the ship as if it collided with a large object while in motion. If the ship depressurized, survivors could still have made their way to an emergency cabin and sealed the bulkheads to await rescue. If there are no survivors, there certainly could be good salvage on the ship. Either way, Captain &lt;&gt; is well aware that Zeltek Commission contracts include incidental rescue obligations for any and all other Zeltek Commission ships you encounter under your contract. From within, the rest of you feel the ship decelerate to a stop. What would you like to do?
Allow the PCs to roleplay for a little bit if they’d like. When somebody approaches the merchant cart, that will trigger the first action roll.Read the following aloud:
The strixwolf is wary of your movement. Let’s make our first roll to see how she reacts! This will be using your Presence trait, so grab your Duality Dice and roll them, then add your Presence. You can also spend a Hope before the roll to add an Experience, if it applies. Then tell me the total and which die rolled higher!
If they rolled a 10 or higher, it is a success! Describe the strixwolf calmly trying to keep her pups out of danger.
If the roll was with Hope, tell the player to gain a Hope.
If the roll was with Fear, gain a Fear. This is also your chance to introduce a consequence to the scene. It should not undermine the success, but rather forward the narrative in an exciting way. You might say:
The mother hoot-howls, as if calling to another strixwolf among the trees. You know you might not be alone for long.
If they rolled a 9 or below, it is a failure. Describe the strixwolf snarling and snapping, angry that the PC is approaching.
If the roll was with Hope, tell the player to gain a Hope. You still get to make a GM move, but because it’s with Hope, it shouldn’t be as bad as it could be. You might say:
With one last snarl, she leans down to have her pups clamber onto her back before taking off into the air, landing on a nearby branch. She is watching your every move.
If the roll was with Fear, things go badly. Gain a Fear and describe the strixwolf snarling at the PC, causing them to mark a Stress.If both dice roll the same number, it’s a critical success! Tell the PC to mark a Hope. They can also clear a Stress, if they have one. Then, describe the strixwolf moving towards the PC, head down, tail wagging. It sits in front of them.]]></description><link>games/daggerheart/starquarry-couriers-quickstart/act-i.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Games/Daggerheart/Starquarry Couriers Quickstart/Act I.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 20:11:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Epilogue]]></title><description><![CDATA[Read the following aloud:
[!]
As you deliver a powerful blow, the ritual ends! The carriage comes falling to the ground as the keystone vibrates with arcane energy. Then, all at once, a soundless explosion erupts from the Whitefire Arcanist, dissipating any last enemies who might remain. The clearing is quiet once again.
Back inside the treehouse, not but an hour later, the keystone sits suspended carefully above a rumbling fire in the hearth.
The Arcanist, who looks even older now than she did before, sits cross-legged in an over-stuffed chair. There is an exhaustion in her voice as she speaks.
“You fought hard. I’m not surprised, of course. The King keeps good company. I’m very glad you were there.”
Give the PCs the chance to wrap up their story with the Arcanist. When conversation stalls or the PCs ask about the keystone, you might say something like:
“The keystone will need a week, maybe more, to allow the magic to settle. I’ll need to watch it carefully to ensure nothing cracks or becomes sentient or anything of the like. You know how it is. And in the meantime, after you rest and gather yourselves, have a nice hot meal and warm bath, I have one more thing to ask of you.”
We pull out of the Arcanist’s home, out of the forest itself, to view the verdant expanse from above, and see twisting stone spires breaking through the treeline, each with a flame flickering within the tower like a beacon. She continues:
“There’s a Spire, just west of here, maybe a few hours walk. I felt it on the way to the ritual. Its power was... strange. The light felt weaker than it should be. I think something might be terribly wrong with the Spirekeeper, and I fear what will happen if its fire is extinguished altogether. When you’re ready, come back, and I’ll give you my map so you can make it there safely. It’s good to have heroes in the Sablewood again.”
And that’s where we’re going to end today’s session.
]]></description><link>games/daggerheart/starquarry-couriers-quickstart/epilogue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Games/Daggerheart/Starquarry Couriers Quickstart/Epilogue.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 01:04:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Act V]]></title><description><![CDATA[Read the following aloud:
On direction from the Arcanist, your carriage pulls into a mysterious clearing in the shape of a perfect circle, the only area of the Sablewood you’ve seen without trees to block out the sky. This is the Open Vale.
Speak to the players as the Arcanist, describing the Open Vale as a place used for strong ritual magic. It’s where she first forged the ward pillars that reside on all four corners of Hush, keeping the village safe. She almost died in that ritual, but is reluctant to say more for fear of angering the Forgotten Gods. Engage the PCs in conversation, then when you’re ready, read the following:
The Arcanist’s antennae perk up in a disconcerting way. “This is good. Stop, stop. Yes, here. Now come help me, I’m old.” This time, she unfolds the carriage as she did with her home and stands over the crate, humming. Her body starts to glow brighter, flickering in the night.
“I will need an hour of time to prepare. You all, enjoy the night air while you can. We’ll be very busy soon.”
Tell the PCs that they will now take a short rest.During a short rest, a PC may choose up to two of the following options.&nbsp;They may choose the same option twice.Describe how you patch yourself up and clear 1d4+1&nbsp;hit points. You may also tend to an ally instead.Describe how you blow off steam or pull yourself together, and clear 1d4+1&nbsp;Stress.Describe how you spend time quickly repairing your armor and clear 1d4+1 marked&nbsp;Armor Slots. You may also repair an ally’s armor instead.Describe how you prepare yourself for the path ahead and gain a&nbsp;Hope. If you choose to Prepare with one or more members of your party, you may each take two Hope.While the PCs are resting, take 1d4&nbsp;Fear&nbsp;as your&nbsp;downtime&nbsp;benefit, then review the stat blocks for adversaries located below and on the next page. These will be used in the final battle.<img src="https://app.demiplane.com/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fimages.demiplane.com%2Fcompendium%2Fdaggerheart%2Fquick-start-adventure%2FZehH1VoTzWsB4ERe%2F00-27-Quickstart-Standee-Skeleton.png&amp;w=750&amp;q=90" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" target="_self" class="is-unresolved">Tier 1 StandardDifficulty:&nbsp;12 |&nbsp;Thresholds:&nbsp;7/none |&nbsp;HP:&nbsp;2 |&nbsp;Stress:&nbsp;1ATK:&nbsp;+0 |&nbsp;Rusted Sword:&nbsp;Melee | 1d6+1 phyGroup Attack - Action:*&nbsp;Spend a Fear&nbsp;to choose a target and spotlight all Ancient Skeletons within&nbsp;Close&nbsp;range of them. Those creatures move into&nbsp;Melee&nbsp;range of the target and make one shared&nbsp;attack roll. On a success, they deal 4&nbsp;physical damage&nbsp;each. Combine this damage.ANCIENT SKELETON BATTLE GUIDEBecause the skeletons have no attack modifier, roll a d20 and ask if it hits the target’s&nbsp;Evasion. On a success, deal 1d6+1&nbsp;physical damage.If the ancient skeletons take 6 or less damage, they mark one&nbsp;hit point. Otherwise, they are defeated.Their&nbsp;Group Attack&nbsp;Feature allows you to activate several skeletons at once to make a powerful attack. When you use this action as your&nbsp;GM move, you must spend a&nbsp;Fear&nbsp;to activate the group attack, then move all skeletons in&nbsp;close&nbsp;range of a target into melee with them. Make one attack roll with a +0 modifier against the PC's Evasion. On a success, deal 4&nbsp;phy damage&nbsp;per skeleton. Add all of this damage up before dealing it to the PC.Act Five // Part TwoRead the following aloud:
The Arcanist lets out a shrill cry, “The keystone has finally responded! Quickly, surround me, the ritual must begin or I’ll lose the pathway! Hurry!” Her body begins glowing brighter and brighter still as her eyes roll backwards into her head and the entire carriage lifts a foot off the ground. A collection of unearthly screeches echo from the woods as nearby creatures are alerted to the arcane energy.
Then place the Whitefire Arcanist standee at the center of the table. Ask the players to also place their standees in the scene. Finally, place four&nbsp;Ancient Skeletons&nbsp;within&nbsp;close&nbsp;range of the Arcanist and two&nbsp;Forest Wraiths&nbsp;within&nbsp;far&nbsp;range, then read the following aloud.
You feel a rumble as four ancient skeletons emerge from the ground, rusted swords in hand, disturbed by the forces of magic being used by the Arcanist. In the distance, two Forest Wraiths float ominously towards you. I’m going to start a&nbsp;countdown die&nbsp;for the ritual, your goal is to hold off the enemies until her work is completed.
Grab a d8 and set it on the table with the 8 facing up. This is a countdown die. It will tick down one number every time an adversary is defeated. It will tick up every time the Whitefire Arcanist is hit with an attack. When the countdown reaches 0, the ritual is complete and the fight will end.Environments can have their own features that let you utilize them in a unique way. For this encounter, you have an environment feature called Vengeance of the Vale.Tier 1 ExplorationVengeance of the Vale - Action:&nbsp;Spend a&nbsp;Fear&nbsp;to summon two additional&nbsp;ancient skeletons&nbsp;from the ground within&nbsp;very close&nbsp;range of a PC.The countdown progresses every time an adversary is defeated, so if it's not moving quickly enough, use&nbsp;Vengeance of the Vale&nbsp;to spawn more skeletons, as they're easy to take down. Have adversaries target the Whitefire Arcanist if no other PCs are within attack range. Her difficulty is 11. She doesn't mark&nbsp;Hit Points&nbsp;or&nbsp;Stress, any damage done to her should be purely narrative.Forest Wraiths can attack from&nbsp;far&nbsp;range with a +3 attack modifier. On a success, they deal 2d6+8&nbsp;
magic damage. They have&nbsp;resistance&nbsp;to&nbsp;physical damage, meaning any incoming physical damage is cut in half (rounded up).Their&nbsp;Memory Delve&nbsp;move makes the target&nbsp;Vulnerable, which means all rolls you make against them are at advantage (roll an additional d20 and take the highest result). This condition doesn’t stack.Pass-Through&nbsp;should be used sparingly to avoid incapacitating the whole party at once. Because this move knocks a PC out of their body and stops them from acting until an adversary is taken down, using the&nbsp;Vengeance of the Vale&nbsp;Encounter Move can be a useful way to generate new, easily defeatable adversaries to avoid this from happening.<br><img src="https://app.demiplane.com/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fimages.demiplane.com%2Fcompendium%2Fdaggerheart%2Fquick-start-adventure%2FZehH1VoTzWsB4ERe%2F00-28-Quickstart-Standee-Wraith.png&amp;w=750&amp;q=90" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" target="_self" class="is-unresolved">Tier 1 BruisersDifficulty:&nbsp;13 |&nbsp;Thresholds:&nbsp;7/14 |&nbsp;HP:&nbsp;6 |&nbsp;Stress:&nbsp;3ATK:&nbsp;+3 |&nbsp;Lifedrain:&nbsp;Far | 2d6+8 magSpectral Body - Passive:&nbsp;The Forest Wraith has&nbsp;resistance&nbsp;to&nbsp;physical damage.Memory Delve - Action:&nbsp;Make an&nbsp;attack roll&nbsp;against a close target. On a success, the Forest Wraith flies into melee and places their hand upon the target’s cheek. Ask the player to describe a terrifying moment from their character’s childhood. Then deal 3d4+9&nbsp;magic damage&nbsp;and make them&nbsp;Vulnerable&nbsp;until their next rest.Pass-Through - Action:&nbsp;Spend a&nbsp;Fear&nbsp;and make an attack roll against a target in melee. On a success, the Forest Wraith passes through the target, pushing their soul from their body momentarily, making them&nbsp;Untethered. They cannot act again until the Ritual Countdown ticks down, clearing this condition. If the entire party becomes&nbsp;Untethered&nbsp;at the same time, they all mark 2&nbsp;Hit Points&nbsp;and their souls return, clearing the condition.If a PC ever marks their last hit point, they make a&nbsp;death move. For the purposes of the Quickstart Adventure, they fall unconscious until they are healed or the danger passes.When the Ritual Die ticks down to 0, move to the Epilogue.]]></description><link>games/daggerheart/starquarry-couriers-quickstart/act-v.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Games/Daggerheart/Starquarry Couriers Quickstart/Act V.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 01:03:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Act IV]]></title><description><![CDATA[Read the following aloud:
Making your way past the homes of the village, then through the farmlands of Hush, you see a variety of crops that have begun to cultivate a thin layer of glowing blue moss over the top of their fruits and vegetables. They pulse softly like a heartbeat as you pass.
Among the thriving groves, you notice that the Sablewood trees in this area have hundreds of unique faces carved into all sides, the eyes peering in every direction.
One tree, taller than the rest, bears the Arcanist’s home, like an overripe fruit. It hangs from a braid of rope, as wide around as a giant’s forearm, tied to a massive branch and counterweighted by a cabin-sized bolder lying at the base of the tree. The stone is marked with a collection of symbols and the cabin windows flash with a soft, yellow-green light.
What would you all like to do?
<img src="https://app.demiplane.com/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fimages.demiplane.com%2Fcompendium%2Fdaggerheart%2Fquick-start-adventure%2FZehH1VoTzWsB4ERe%2F00-16-Quickstart-pg33.png&amp;w=828&amp;q=90" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" target="_self" class="is-unresolved">Give the players the option to roleplay and problem solve. Use the section below as guidance, or create your own.
If they try to call to the Arcanist from below,&nbsp;there is no response, but the light within still flickers.
If they try to cut the counterweight rope,&nbsp;it will immediately blast them backwards a few feet, dealing a point of Stress.
If they try to climb the tree,&nbsp;its an&nbsp;Agility Roll with a&nbsp;difficulty&nbsp;of 13. On a failure, a limb of the tree grabs them, gently sets them down on the forest floor, then resumes its original form.
When they finally do something to successfully get the Arcanist’s attention,&nbsp;use the following to describe her as she emerges from her cabin to greet them.
A seven-foot mix of humanoid and firefly, the Arcanist is a faerie that moves in a combination of both very slow and suddenly jerky motions. Though her expressions are difficult to read, her emotions are very clear in her voice. She is old but spry, and she eyes the group mischieviously.
“Are you the group Emeris sent from the capital? Oh my, you’re rather late aren’t you. Come in, come in.”
As the Arcanist lowers her home and invites you inside, you’ll notice the treehouse is surprisingly spacious. The main room is a crowd of potion bottles, spellbooks, runes, plants, and small creatures of all kinds. But, no one could classify this place as messy. It’s clear that if anyone moved a single item even an inch, the old faerie would notice.
<br><img src="https://app.demiplane.com/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fimages.demiplane.com%2Fcompendium%2Fdaggerheart%2Fquick-start-adventure%2FZehH1VoTzWsB4ERe%2F00-29-Chara-Archanist.png&amp;w=750&amp;q=90" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" target="_self" class="is-unresolved">Let the players roleplay with the Arcanist. Make her curious about their journey, the NPC who directed them towards her house, and how each of them have imagined they might die one day.Once she’s had enough conversation, the Arcanist will ask about the package from King Emeris. In order to inspect it in safety, she will magically unfold her home as if it were a blossoming flower. She’ll hurry the players to get the crate inside before closing the cabin back up, now just a bit bigger. When she opens the delivery, read the section below aloud:
Inside King Emeris’ package lies a massive stone with a lion’s face carved into it. Marlowe, you recognize this as the keystone of the capital city gate’s main archway. The Arcanist nods sagely as soon as she sees it, saying: “Of course the King would keep this delivery secret. If anyone knew your city was no longer warded, you would be conquered before sunrise.” With this ominous warning, she starts to unfurl her treehouse yet again. “We must travel to the Open Vale to revitalize the ward. But such an effort of magic will attract dangerous creatures from the darkest reaches of the Sablewood. I’ll need your help.”
If the players seem enthusiastic about helping, you should cut straight to the Open Vale, transitioning into Act Five. Otherwise, you can encourage the players to describe their time traveling with the eccentric Whitefire Arcanist.]]></description><link>games/daggerheart/starquarry-couriers-quickstart/act-iv.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Games/Daggerheart/Starquarry Couriers Quickstart/Act IV.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:57:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Act III]]></title><description><![CDATA[Read the following aloud:
The path leads you further into the forest until you spot a large stone pillar, carved top to bottom in ancient dwarven symbols. This denotes one corner of the peaceful village of Hush. When you pass beyond the stone marker, you feel a small sensation like the pop of a bubble, then the sounds of friendly chatter become louder.
Though the trees of the Sablewood are unchanged here, there is a distinctive safe and comforting air. A few smiling faces turn to you as your carriage rolls in, waving or casting a warm greeting toward the party. There is lively music drifting your direction from the tavern at the center of town.
You know you need to find the Whitefire Arcanist to deliver the package from the King. What would you like to do?
If the players would like to talk to an NPC, you can choose one of the options below.Wildborne&nbsp;Human&nbsp;- (they/them)A young child who will not stop wiggling—it’s clear how they earned their name. They are often busy scurrying up the trees in town, lighting the lanterns that hang from the branches. They know the fastest ways through the village. If the PCs approach, they are curious what life is like outside of Hush.Dwarf&nbsp;- (she/her)An older woman with a thick beard carrying a barrel of ale. She is happy to stand and talk to the party (she will keep the barrel on her shoulder the entire time). If the PCs approach, she wants to know the name of every member of the party’s weapons and the date they were forged.Loreborne&nbsp;Clank&nbsp;- (he/him)A soft-spoken clank (a humanoid robot) of indeterminate age. He bears a number of small scratches across his metallic shoulder where an alert but friendly fox-bat rests. He is playing an unknown game that uses cards and acorns. If the PCs approach, he is curious about the Thistlefolk and asks if you encountered any on your way.During their discussion, choose an additional NPC from the list above. The second will be a friend that has knowledge of where the Whitefire Arcanist lives. They last saw this person at the tavern and send you in its direction.For example, your PCs might meet Fidget in town. After some conversation and coaxing, Fidget points the party to the tavern to meet Lausa.Read the following aloud:
The Clover Tavern is a sight to behold, with six curving stories climbing the trunk of an ancient tree. This is the heart of the community, always crowded with music and good-natured conversation. Newcomers to the bar must take off their shoes and hang them over a line that stretches across the bar’s ground floor. Inevitably, by the time visitors leave, their shoes will be shined and filled with small trinkets. As you enter, what would you like to do?
Let the players roleplay here for a bit, introduce them to a barkeep or a friendly local who asks them to hang their shoes on the line. Let them explore the different levels of the tavern, and if you feel comfortable, ask some of your players to participate in describing details about it.
How does the second floor of this tavern look so wildly different than the first? What smell permeates the air throughout this place? What unique custom do the locals seem to participate in every time you walk in the room? If they ask around, the PCs will find out the people of Hush are currently celebrating the Firstmoss Festival—the time when the new crops in the Sunless Farms have the first layer of moss growing upon them, meaning they’re beginning to ripen for the season. It’s a celebration of the arrival of spring, and of the abundance of fresh fruits and vegetables the town will soon have. There is a good-natured arm wrestling competition, a stone-painting class, and a small marketplace full of homemade trinkets.
When you’re ready, guide the players in finding an NPC who will help them. If they bypassed asking someone in town, just use one of the NPCs from the list here instead. After a few exchanges, you can have the NPC say something like:
The Arcanist is quite busy, but if you’ve traveled so far, I’m sure she’ll be more than hospitable. We would be lost without her. She keeps this whole place protected by a powerful ward so that no dangers from the Sablewood can pass into town. You’ll find her house to the south, through the farmland. It’s hanging from one of the old Sablewood trees, you can’t miss it.
When the PCs are ready, set them off towards the Arcanist.]]></description><link>games/daggerheart/starquarry-couriers-quickstart/act-iii.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Games/Daggerheart/Starquarry Couriers Quickstart/Act III.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:52:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Act II]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let the events of the previous act play out, allowing the players to roleplay and take other actions. Use the scenarios below for guidance.If they search the merchant cart, you can talk about the cart being stripped of all valuables and showcase the dead driver with a mangled arm, picked over by the strixwolf family for food. If the PCs inspect the body further, they might find that the driver had his neck slit.If they attack the strixwolf, have them make an attack roll against it at a difficulty of 10. On a success, they deal damage using their weapon. The pups will flee.If they fail any rolls to interact with the strixwolf, it will pull its pups onto its back and fly into a nearby tree, watching the adventurers from above.If they try to find signs of something strange, they see the remnants of thorny bramble tangled around the wheel of the carriage and strewn across on the road.If they want to move the merchant cart out of the way, are taking steps to get their carriage moving again, or are trying to leave the trail, jump to "Ambushed!"Strixwolf Mother
Tier 1 Standard
Bite - Melee - 1d6+3 phy Attack Modifier: +1 Difficulty: 10 Major 4 | Severe 8 HP: OOO Stress: OOOWhen the moment feels right, or one of the above scenarios triggers it, ask a PC who seems like they are paying attention to their surroundings to make an Instinct Roll with a difficulty of 14.On a success, they notice eyes watching them from the darkness beyond the trail. If it was with Fear, gain a Fear and have the PC mark a Stress. Use the “See Them Coming” prompts.On a failure, they are immediately ambushed. If it was with Fear, gain a Fear and have the PC also mark a Stress. Use the “Ambushed!” prompts.Read the following aloud:
You hear the sounds of a branch snapping and turn to see four Thistlefolk sneaking through the underbrush, attempting to get the jump on your party. The overturned cart was a distraction, but their plan didn’t work. I’m going to set up a map!
Read the following aloud:
In a whirlwind of cracking branches and unsheathed blades, a group of four Thistlefolk jump out from the brush alongside the road. The overturned cart was an ambush! They stand before you, weapons drawn, blocking the road. They'll go first. I’m going to set up a battle map!
Take the forest terrain you’ve cut out and ask for your players to help you spread it across the table to build a map. You may also encourage them to grab other items from around the room to add terrain to the map. Build out the playspace together.Then, place the overturned merchant’s cart on the table and ask the players to put their miniatures nearby, where they think they would be in the scene, along with their carriage. Finally, take the Thistlefolk Ambusher standees and the Thistlefolk Thief, and put them in Close range of the PCs.On the next page, you’ll find the stat blocks for the Ambushers and Thief. You’ll use those stat blocks to run the remainder of this encounter. Remember to make the battle your own. Decide what the Thistlefolk look like in detail, describe the scene as if the players were watching a movie or reading a book, and if you’re comfortable with it, ask them to participate in building out the scene as well. This can be as easy as asking them to describe their attack or their evasion in detail, but you might also involve them further—ask them what unique clothing item the Ambushers are all wearing, or the interesting fighting style they seem to employ. You might also ask what level of violence the players are comfortable with. Are they looking to kill the enemies? Incapacitate them? Knock them out?If the players were ambushed, the Thistlefolk act first. We can see this reflected in their feature, “Ambush.” Read the following aloud:
Having the upper hand, the three Thistlefolk Ambushers rush you! Because of their Ambush feature, they get to make an attack immediately. This only happens when they enter the scene, so it won’t be like this every time. But right now, they are slashing at you with daggers, protected by armor made of polished stones.
Move the ambushers into melee with the PC closest to them. Then follow the attack guide below for each Ambusher.If the players spotted the Ambushers coming, they get to act first. Read the following aloud:
You stand at the ready, having spotted the Thistlefolk before they could ambush you! You all get to act first, who wants to start us off?
standard stat blocks x3Use the Ambushers to keep the party’s attention while the thief attempts to steal their carriageOn the Thistlefolk Ambusher, you’ll notice the stat block is listed as "Reference" with three other smaller stat blocks below it. This is how Daggerheart represents three adversaries that all have the same stats. Instead of repeating all of the information three times, it is in one centralized area.When you make an attack against a PC, roll a d20 and add its attack modifier (+1), then compare it to the PC’s Evasion. If it hits, make a damage roll using 1d8+5. Ask them to compare the total to their damage thresholds, use armor if they'd like, and mark their hit point(s).When you make an attack against a PC, roll a d20 and add its attack modifier (+3), then compare it to the PC’s Evasion. If it hits, make a damage roll using 2d4+3. Ask them to compare the total to their damage thresholds, use armor if they'd like, and mark their hit points. If they’re using Back Off, on a success deal the damage and move the PC’s standee a direction of your choice in far range of where they previously were.When an adversary is hit with damage, compare the amount to their thresholds, then mark the appropriate hit points. When you mark their last hit point, they are defeated.Leader stat blockThe encounter ends when all adversaries are defeated. Clean up the map, then encourage the PCs to describe a montage of the remaining travel time to Hush.]]></description><link>games/daggerheart/starquarry-couriers-quickstart/act-ii.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Games/Daggerheart/Starquarry Couriers Quickstart/Act II.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 23:01:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vegetor]]></title><description><![CDATA[stuff like fungril, sylvaneth, arborec, and other plantfolk]]></description><link>setting/species/vegetor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Vegetor.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:16:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sauroid]]></title><description><![CDATA[stuff like galapa/turtlefolk, dinosaurfolk, etc.]]></description><link>setting/species/sauroid.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Sauroid.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:15:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Herbitor]]></title><description><![CDATA[stuff like firbolg, minotaur, satyr, etc.]]></description><link>setting/species/herbitor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Herbitor.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:15:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Faerie]]></title><description><![CDATA[small diminutive winged folk]]></description><link>setting/species/faerie.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Faerie.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:14:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Carnitor]]></title><description><![CDATA[stuff like catfolk, dogfolk, etc.]]></description><link>setting/species/carnitor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Carnitor.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:14:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Raulus Ignu POIs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Trickster god created the Everything Factory and the earworm is an omen of the god's escape from Raulus Ignu
founded by a thief
home to the Fountain of Paupers is a healing a spring new cyborg form of life has just emerged here
moves to <a data-href="The Everything Factory" href="novels/the-everything-factory.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Everything Factory</a>
The Iron FenA trickster god was set free from their prison and needs to be recaptured.
Wants to pull a heist on/with/of a hag
Where is the god hiding or going? A sundered star system
Where or with what can the god be captured? An experimental energy shield.
Everyone has the same strange song stuck in their heads and they want to know why.
Describe the song. Fairy-touched.
Who might know something? A dwarven asteroid miner
What are two possible causes? An omen; a DJ. by floes that are a source of a precious fuel
mysterious graffiti symbols have appeared all over the area
was the pet project of a petty god
The Everything Factory]]></description><link>novels/raulus-ignu-pois.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Novels/Raulus Ignu POIs.canvas</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:13:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[High Level Notes]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Earthsea/Tolkien tone
Lost love interest is Romali, Queen of Exiles, an ascended Firbolg god that keeps a massive living space station planetoid as her domain, with which she has merged to some degree
Snibs was godsbound by the Mad God Yudwichinda (an exiled Elven god?), who has become infatuated with the Queen of Exiles when they first encountered her; Yudwichinda's goals and plans are as inscrutable as their mind Snibs' cosmic leap involved a heist on a vast ecumenopolis to steal a set of ancient silver alloy eating utensils held in a museum on the planet; afterwards, Yudwichinda released Snibs and did not even take the heisted artifacts; this is also where Snibs gained/stole his ship, the Carved and Curated Shoulders of Giants, referred as “Carvey” for short Yudwichinda’s ultimate aim is to ascend Snibs as a god Is looking for a way back to Romali and her station, which wanders Carvey includes an arcanotechnological AI that is powered by a Soul Urn—soul urn power passively captures spiritual energy (though some say actual spirits and souls) from dying sentients within a few astronomical units range Bridge - medical/lab - quarters - mess - power/engines - cargo Snibs slides into the relevant star system because the ship system that shields his and other sapient passengers’ harmonies (axial harmony/soul/etc.) from being irrecoverably tainted by the carvey’s traversal through aplanar space (traveling outside the plane of the Cosm’s universe and through the Meta Axes)--without this, practical travel across the Cosm will so thoroughly corrupt Snibs that he’ll go mad
Snibs is an innate mage, though he doesn't realize it at the start of the novel—he is able to tap into time magic
Yudwichinda is puppeteering Snibs trip to Raulus Ignu in order to release their twin-aspect god Chinwiyudda, God of Self-deception, who has been locked away beneath the Fountain of Paupers and can only be released with time magic focused by a lens of energy magic and a non-godsbound mage as soon as Snibs arrives in proximity to Raulus Ignu, he begins to hear whispers and feel the influence of Chinwiyudda working his mind, which he believes are just the trauma of being godsleapt and the after effects specifically of being godsbound to Yudwichinda Planet is called Raulus Ignu Life: 1 (null) Reason: 6 (beacon) Temperature: 6 (beacon) Matter: 5 (high) Energy: 3 (low-mid) Time: 1 (null) ]]></description><link>novels/high-level-notes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Novels/High Level Notes.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:12:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[General]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Cosm, which is the common name for the “galaxy,” of Cosmic Leap is actually two galaxies oriented orthogonal to each other and collided nearly halfway somewhat like in the image below. However, this is occurring at a cosmic pace so it is totally unfelt by most mortal species. It has also been happening for so long that for the majority of inhabitants, this has always been the galaxy’s (galaxies’) structure—although some incredibly long-lived entities, like certain gods, may have memory of their respective galaxy pre-collision. While most wouldn’t realize it, technically one galaxy is home to the “standard” high fantasy species and cultures, like elves, humans, dwarves, gnomes, halflings, etc. The other is where the more “alien” species long ago developed. Nevertheless, at the “current” point in time, all species are so thoroughly distributed across the Cosm that none would recognize any other as particularly alien to the Cosm. Though, of course, many planets favor a particular species and may even be homeworlds to that species, like the elves of Aelfweld for example.Magic suffuses the Cosm and while not universally used or accessible, is effectively known by everyone and a very common sight. The Cosm, and it is theorized this entire universe, is really a quivering membrane of mana stretched across six elemental dimensions. Practicing magic is a matter of a kind of “plucking” or “beating” of the membrane so that its vibrations resonate along these various elemental axes in different ways, thus invoking various effects in the Cosm (and potentially in any affected planes as well). The Cosm is not distributed evenly across the elemental axes, though, and some parts of the Cosm may be strong in some planes and utterly void in others. Some may even be a confluence of all the dimensions at once and others none at all! The six Meta Axes, as they are referred to by academics, are: Life, Reason, Temperature, Matter, Energy, Time.It is important to understand that the Meta Axes are not planes, though the membrane constituting the Cosm may be considered a plane, and the Meta Axes are, as far as anyone knows, not directly accessible as any sort of space in their own right. Rather, an unknown number of planes are able to extend across the Meta Axes and all are effectively orthogonal to each other just as much as the Meta Axes are to themselves. That is to say, there may be punctuated locations where travel between these membranes or planes is possible, but they never overlap. These other planes are where some theorize various afterlives are located. Some planes also may adhere very closely to one or another particular Meta Axis and so give the appearance of being a “Plane of Matter” or “Plane of Energy” but they are not, and other planes may be similarly closely hewn to the same Meta Axis. Moreover, travel between these planes is not recommended as there is never a guarantee that they abide by the same physics and metaphysics of the Cosm.As mentioned, there are all manner of entities of various degrees of power within the Cosm, including gods. The “gods” of the Cosm are beings of immense power, who vary in nature as much as they vary in how they achieved their powers (including simply being elemental expressions of the Cosm), but they are all mobile confluences of all Meta Axes. Every god effectively forces every Meta Axis to intersect upon their being, and thus can warp and weave the Cosm in unfathomable ways. The Cosm’s gods are myriad, but the Cosm’s span is also inconceivably immense—gods are powerful but space is BIG. As a result, mortals in the Cosm have simply learned to try to avoid unknown gods as much as they can. Given the vastness of the Cosm, even the most active and mobile gods are unlikely to ever descend upon more than a vanishingly small fraction of the Cosm’s inhabitants in any arbitrarily large span of time.When mortals are visited by a god, though, some are inevitably pulled into that god’s inscrutable plan and displaced randomly throughout the Cosm as a result once they serve their purpose to the god. This is typically referred to as a Cosmic Leap and those actively working under a god as godsbound (and those released from service are referred to as godsleapt). The gods share one more universal trait, and that is their ability to enthrall a mortal’s mind. When someone becomes godsbound, they are not merely forced to do what their god wants, but it simply seems completely logical and obvious to do so. The godsbound want to do what their god needs. Once they are godsleapt, their reasoning and feelings when godsbound may seem completely foreign, but it is universal that godsbound are not coerced to do their gods’ bidding—it’s just something they feel is obviously the correct thing to do at the time. It is unclear if this enthrallment is something gods do intentionally or is just a consequence of their mere presence. Those who believe the enthrallment is a sort of knotting of the Axial Harmony that makes up every living thing’s “soul” typically also ascribe to the theory that godsbinding is a natural consequence of gods’ warping of the Meta Axes around them.These provide general themes of the driving conflicts that exist within the Cosm.
Non-godsbound vs godsbound
Able to traverse interstellar vs limited regional governments Axial tears vs normal space
Nascent empire(s) vs independent systems or even planets Lost technology vs hidden threats
Invention vs inviting harm into the Cosm Local cultures tend to be insular vs inadvertently welcoming a threat
Safer to trust few or no one vs found family and/or culture
In addition to the Meta Axes of Magic, there are two primary ways inhabitants of the Cosm interact with magic. The first are those with innate ability due to some quirk of their Axial Harmony, often referred to simply as “innates.” There is perhaps some small degree of heritability associated with innates, but it must be fairly negligible as an innate may seemingly arise in any bloodline and the likelihood of an innate being born to innate parents is nowhere near a guarantee. Perhaps one in a hundred thousand is an innate and their gifts are almost immediately apparent upon birth, whether artificial or natural, with minimal variance across sapient species (though this rule of thumb does not seem to apply to non-sapients).The other way to wield magic is broadly referred to as “academic” use of magic. Whereas innates summon their application of magic from within and manage it largely by intuition, academic magic users treat it as a field of scholarly study and must learn from those who came before or by means of experimentation and observation. Academic magic is available to all and is by far the most common way to manipulate the mana underlaying all existence across the various Meta Axes that are accessible in an area. Different cultures approach academic magic differently—some consider it a field of maths, some call it the learning and true naming of things, some consider it the accumulation of engrams, and endless other variations on its practice—but all treat it as a scholarly and learned pursuit.The most critical practical difference between innate and academic magic is that innates can use their magic anywhere, regardless of the accessible Meta Axes of magic in their current location while, in contrast, academics are limited by the magic available around them. When in a null zone, most academics are incapable of even the simplest spell of they have not taken proper precautions, but a nearby innate may nevertheless fling summoned orbs of varying temperature, hasten time in a local area, or even exude magic possibly to the benefit of the nearby and otherwise powerless academic. In addition, generally speaking, innates are bound to one Meta Axis of magic or even a particular sort of expression of that Axis, though this is not a hard rule and every locale has legends of innates able to harness multiple Axes. There are even theories that postulate an innate who is able to harness all Axes necessarily ascends to godhood, though such an event has never been recorded or at least published.]]></description><link>setting/general.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/General.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:11:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cay System]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Raulus Ignu, primary planet single small moon orbiting, called El, that orbits perpendicular to the planet's ring large ringed continental planet, temperate and seasonal
- mountains are defining terrain characteristic, fairly thick atmosphere and higher than 9.8 gravity
- experiences sporadic meteors from ring, which is itself fed by a matter axis wellspring in orbit
- exotic materials enter into the ring and subsequently may fall to Raulus Ignu as meteors Planet Snibs’ first story takes place on
]]></description><link>setting/locations/cay-system.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Locations/Cay System.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:08:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aelfweld]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Entire system has been converted into a Dyson sphere megacity Loosely divided into regions corresponding to Elf phenotypes Regions further subdivided into tribe/ethnic areas (as per most worlds)--not a monoculture/habitat Phenotypes:
- Bone Elves
- Green Elves
- Rind Elves
- Void Elves Region of space is null space--it is never orthogonal to any other axes and so magic naturally is severely constrained/non-existent in Aelfweld Resulted in Elves being extremely technologically advanced without reliance on magic, and correspondingly magically primitive/poor--all magitech are from trade Elves at some point in their history "killed" their gods long before the Great Work (the building of the Dyson sphere) Originally, Elves were locked in perpetual and bitter war between all tribes/groups, each one led by a respective god. They eventually realized that the gods were manifestations of their own communal wills and there was no real reason for the constant warfare. A movement overtook the species to simply stop believing in, depending upon, or respecting their gods and come together in the Great Work. Elven gods are now conniving trickster gods in exile--an expression of Elves’ belief in them--and offer little to no real guidance to the Elves. However, once the Great Work completed, the tribes still fell back into their old patterns of fighting and scheming. As a result, Aelfweld's enormous polity is rife with tribal interests and political games. ]]></description><link>setting/locations/aelfweld.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Locations/Aelfweld.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:07:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Drakmen]]></title><description><![CDATA[dargunpeeps]]></description><link>setting/species/drakmen.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Drakmen.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:06:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fremic]]></title><description><![CDATA[Antfolk/insectoid]]></description><link>setting/species/fremic.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Fremic.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:05:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ethereal]]></title><description><![CDATA[Energy goofs]]></description><link>setting/species/ethereal.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Ethereal.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:04:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Belle]]></title><description><![CDATA[jellyfish]]></description><link>setting/species/belle.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Belle.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:04:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Halfling]]></title><description><![CDATA[Teardrop eared shorties not on space ships]]></description><link>setting/species/halfling.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Halfling.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:04:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gnome]]></title><description><![CDATA[Pointy eared shorties on space ships]]></description><link>setting/species/gnome.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Gnome.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:04:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dwarf]]></title><description><![CDATA[Asteroid dwellers]]></description><link>setting/species/dwarf.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Dwarf.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:04:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Human]]></title><description><![CDATA[Erpaderp humies]]></description><link>setting/species/human.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Human.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:04:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elf]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tall and slender hominids, Elves could be mistaken for an offshoot of humanity (or Humans an offshoot of Aelfinity if you were to ask an Elf) but there is no evidence that this is the case. Elves are even more varied than humans, their physical form tending to take on visual characteristics based on the environment in which they’re born. As a result, Elven parents of one type may have children of an altogether different type or even types. All Elves, regardless of variety, have long pointy ears that tend to droop down at the tip (and are consistently primary focuses of decoration across nearly all Elven cultures). Elven eyes are of a uniform color and do not display a differentiated pupil and iris like the majority of other common hominids.There are four standard groupings of Elves (though there may be more as a result of Elves residing in unusual places), consisting of: Bone Elves, Rind Elves, Void Elves, and Green Elves. Rind Elves and Bone Elves are the most common and dominate their artificial homeworld of Aelfweld, which is a Dyson sphere ecumenopolis. Rind Elves live on the exterior surface of Aelfweld, which is provided a diurnal cycle by a system of artificial miniature stars set into orbit around Aelfweld, and are a grey hued people sometimes taking on very light pastel tints. Bone Elves reside within the internal structure of Aelfweld and even the interior surface that faces its encased star. Bone Elves are dark hued, typically very dark shades of reds and oranges, though deep greens and blues are not unusual. Void Elves and Green Elves arise from those Elven lineages that migrated off of Aelfweld. Green Elves are not necessarily green, although this is by far the most common tone, but they can be found in natural environments and worlds. Green Elves have a deep pastel hued complexion, usually greens or blues and sometimes even various shades of red, purple, or pink. Void Elves make their homes in space, either as nomadic colonies of roving ships or settled into some sort of asteroid, space station, or other stable non-planetary structure relatively detached from a single star. Void Elves have a jet black complexion that, under bright broad spectrum light, may display a gentle rainbow sheen like an oil slick.]]></description><link>setting/species/elf.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Elf.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:04:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Automata]]></title><description><![CDATA[A catch all for non-biological sapient beings, Automata come in an infinite variety of configurations and capabilities. Some are as simple as rolling geometric shapes, and others may push the species definition to its limit with their configuration closely mirroring a biological entity but made out of tiny machines or malleable larger machines. The key factor distinguishing an Automata from a mere computing machine is that it is bound with an Axial Harmony and when it dies, this Axial Harmony dissipates or detaches (i.e., it has a spirit and can leave behind a ghost).]]></description><link>setting/species/automata.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Automata.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 10:03:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Starquarry Courriers Ritual Location]]></title><link>games/daggerheart/starquarry-courriers-ritual-location.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Games/Daggerheart/Starquarry Courriers Ritual Location.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 18:20:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elemtor]]></title><link>setting/species/elemtor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Elemtor.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 12:33:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Giant]]></title><link>setting/species/giant.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Giant.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 12:30:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Orc]]></title><link>setting/species/orc.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Setting/Species/Orc.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 12:30:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Iron Fen]]></title><description><![CDATA[
founded by a thief
home to the Fountain of Paupers is a healing a spring new cyborg form of life has just emerged here
moves to <a data-href="The Everything Factory" href="novels/the-everything-factory.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Everything Factory</a>
]]></description><link>novels/the-iron-fen.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Novels/The Iron Fen.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 05:00:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Everything Factory]]></title><description><![CDATA[
by floes that are a source of a precious fuel
mysterious graffiti symbols have appeared all over the area
was the pet project of a petty god
]]></description><link>novels/the-everything-factory.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Novels/The Everything Factory.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 04:59:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><link>novels/snibs'-story/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Novels/Snibs' Story/Index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 04:38:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>